I thought I'd begin with a scene of war.
فكرت بأن أبدأ بمشهد للحرب
There was little to warn of the danger ahead.
كان هناك ماينذر بخطر قادم .
The Iraqi insurgent had placed the IED,
كانت المقاومة العراقية قد وضعت قنبلة مصنوعة محليا،
an Improvised Explosive Device,
عبوة ناسفة,
along the side of the road with great care.
على طول جانب الطريق بطريقة محكمة.
By 2006, there were more than 2,500
بحلول عام 2006 كانت تقع أزيد من 2500
of these attacks every single month,
من هذه الهجمات كل شهر،
and they were the leading cause of
وقد كانت السبب الرئيسي
casualties among American soldiers
في الخسائر المسجلة في صفوف الجيش الأمريكي
and Iraqi civilians.
والمدنيين العراقيين.
The team that was hunting for this IED
كان الفريق المكلف باكتشاف العبوات الناسفة
is called an EOD team—
يدعى فريق التخلص من الذخائر المتفجرة--
Explosives Ordinance Disposal—and
التخلص من الذخائر المتفجرة--
they're the pointy end of the spear in the
إنهم بمثابة حاملي الرماح
American effort to suppress these roadside bombs.
بالنسبة للجهود الأمريكية لإزالة القنابل المزروعة على الطريق.
Each EOD team goes out on about
كان فريق التخلص من الذخائر يخرج على إثر
600 of these bomb calls every year,
600 من المكالمات المبلغة عن القنابل كل سنة،
defusing about two bombs a day.
نازعا فتيل قنبلتين يوميا.
Perhaps the best sign of how valuable they
ربما يكون الدليل الأفضل على أهمية هذه الفرق
are to the war effort, is that
بالنسبة للجهود الحربية، أن
the Iraqi insurgents put a $50,000 bounty
المتمردين العراقيين وضعوا مكافأة قدرها 50000$
on the head of a single EOD soldier.
مقابل رأس كل جندي متخصص في التخلص من الذخائر.
Unfortunately, this particular call
للأسف، هذا النداء الخاص
would not end well.
لن ينتهي على خير.
By the time the soldier advanced close
في الوقت الذي كان فيه الجندي يقترب
enough to see the telltale wires
بما فيه الكفاية ليتمكن من رؤية الأسلاك المنبهة
of the bomb, it exploded in a wave of flame.
المرتبطة بالقنبلة ، انفجرت هذه الأخيرة في موجة من اللهب.
Now, depending how close you are
الآن، على قدر قربك من القنبلة
and how much explosive has been packed
وكذا كمية المتفجرات المحشوة فيها
into that bomb, it can cause death
يمكن أن تتسبب في الوفاة
or injury. You have to be as far as
أو الإصابة بجروح ، عليك أن تكون أبعد بحوالي
50 yards away to escape that.
50 ياردةللنجاة من ذلك.
The blast is so strong it can even break
يكون الانفجار قويا لدرجة يمكن أن تكسر
your limbs, even if you're not hit.
أطرافك، حتى وإن لم تصبك.
That soldier had been on top of the bomb.
كان ذلك الجندي يقف على القنبلة.
And so when the rest of the team advanced
وهكذا عندما تقدمت بقية الفريق
they found little left. And that night the unit's
لم يجدوا إلا آثارا قليلة، وفي تلك الليلة
commander did a sad duty, and he wrote
أدى قائد الوحدة واجبا حزينا، وكتب
a condolence letter back to the United
رسالة تعزية إلى الولايات
States, and he talked about how hard the
المتحدة، وتحدث كم أن
loss had been on his unit, about the fact
هذا الفقدان كان أمرا قاسيا على وحدته, و على أنهم
that they had lost their bravest soldier,
فقدوا جنديهم الأكثر شجاعة،
a soldier who had saved their lives
الجندي الذي أنقذ حياتهم
many a time.
في مرات عديدة.
And he apologized
وقد اعتذر
for not being able to bring them home.
على عدم تمكنه من إعادته إلى الديار.
But then he talked up the silver lining
لكن بعدها تحدث عن العبرة
that he took away from the loss.
التي استخلصها من هذا الفقدان.
"At least," as he wrote, "when a robot dies,
"على الأقل" كما كتب "عندما يموت روبوت
you don't have to write a letter
لا تكون مضطرا لكتابة رسالة
to its mother."
إلى أمه."
That scene sounds like science fiction,
يبدو هذا المشهد أشبه بالخيال العلمي،
but is battlefield reality already.
لكنه أمر وقع في ساحة معركة حقيقية.
The soldier in that case
الجندي في هذه الحالة
was a 42-pound robot called a PackBot.
كان روبوتا يزن 42 باوندا يدعى باكبو.
The chief's letter went, not to some
لم تذهب رسالة القائد
farmhouse in Iowa like you see
إلى بيت في مزرعة بولاية لوا كما ترون
in the old war movies, but went to
في أفلام الحروب القديمة، بل ذهبت إلى
the iRobot Company, which is
شركة آي روبوت، التي
named after the Asimov novel
سميت على اسم رواية اسيموف
and the not-so-great Will Smith movie,
و فيلم ويل سميث غير المذهل
and... um... (Laughter)...
ثم ... اممم... (ضحك)...
if you remember that
إذا تذكرتم أنه
in that fictional world, robots started out
في العالم الخيالي ، بدأت الروبوتات
carrying out mundane chores, and then
بالاهتمام بالأعمال المنزلية المضنية، ومن ثم
they started taking on life-and-death decisions.
بدأت الروبوتات تأخذ خيارات مصيرية.
That's a reality we face today.
هذه هي الحقيقة التي نواجهها اليوم.
What we're going to do is actually just
ما سنقوم به في الواقع
flash a series of photos behind me that
هو عرض سريع لسلسلة من الصور خلفي
show you the reality of robots used in war
التي تظهر واقع الروبوتات المستعملة في الحروب
right now or already at the prototype stage.
كما هي الآن ، أو حينما كانت عبارة عن نماذج مبدئية.
It's just to give you a taste.
سيعطيكم هذا نكهة أولية.
Another way of putting it is you're not
طريقة أخرى لتقديم هذا هو أنكم
going to see anything that's powered
لن تروا شيئا مما طورته مدعوما
by Vulcan technology, or teenage
من طرف شركة فولكان تيكنولوجي،
wizard hormones or anything like that.
أو أي هرمون مرافق لسن المراهقة أو أي من هذا القبيل.
This is all real. So why don't we
كل هذا حقيقي . إذن لم لا
go ahead and start those pictures.
نتابع و نبدأ بمشاهدة هذه الصور.
Something big is going on in war today,
خطب عظيم يحدث في الحروب اليوم،
and maybe even the history of humanity
وربما حتى في تاريخ الإنسانية
itself. The U.S. military went into Iraq with
نفسها. ذهبت القوات الأمريكية إلى العراق
a handful of drones in the air.
مصحوبة بمجموعة صغيرة من الطائرات من دون طيار.
We now have 5,300.
لدينا الآن 5300.
We went in with zero unmanned ground
ذهبنا إلى هناك من دون أي نظام أرضي
systems. We now have 12,000.
من دون طيار ، لدينا الآن 12000.
And the tech term "killer application"
و المصطلح التكنولوجي " التطبيق القاتل"
takes on new meaning in this space.
أصبح يأخذ معنى جديدا في هذا الفضاء.
And we need to remember that we're
وعلينا أن نتذكر أننا
talking about the Model T Fords,
نتحدث عن نموذج تي فوردز
the Wright Flyers, compared
نشرات رايت ، مقارنة
to what's coming soon.
بما هو قادم عما قريب.
That's where we're at right now.
هنا حيث ننتواجد الآن.
One of the people that I recently met with
أحد الأشخاص الذين التقيتهم مؤخرا
was an Air Force three-star general, and he
كان جنرالا في سلاح الجو ذا ثلاث نجمات، وكان
said basically, where we're headed very
أن قال بالأساس ، أننا حيث كنا متوجهين
soon is tens of thousands of robots
تتواجد عشرات الآلاف من الروبوتات
operating in our conflicts, and these
العاملة في نزاعاتنا، وهذه
numbers matter, because we're not just
وهذه الأرقام مهمة ، لأننا لسنا فقط
talking about tens of thousands of today's
نتحدث عن عشرات الآلاف من روبوتات اليوم
robots, but tens of thousands of these
بل عن عن عشرات الآلاف من هذه
prototypes and tomorrow's robots, because
النماذج المبدئية و روبوتات الغد لأنه
of course, one of the things that's operating
بطبيعة الحال،أحد العوامل المؤثرة
in technology is Moore's Law,
في التكنولوجيا هو قانون مور،
that you can pack in more and more
الذي يمكنك من إضافة المزيد و المزيد
computing power into those robots, and so
من القوة المعلوماتية في تلك الروبوتات، و بالتالي
flash forward around 25 years,
استطلاع 25 سنة قادمة،
if Moore's Law holds true,
إذا صدق قانون مور،
those robots will be close to a billion times
فإن تلك الروبوتات ستصل إلى ما يقارب البليون
more powerful in their computing than today.
أكثر قوة في نظمها المعلوماتية مما هي عليه اليوم.
And so what that means is the kind of
وهذا ما يعني أن
things that we used to only talk about at
ما اعتدنا فقط التحدث عنه
science fiction conventions like Comic-Con
في اتفاقيات الخيال العلمي، مثل كوميك كون
have to be talked about in the halls
يجب تدارسه في أروقة
of power and places like the Pentagon.
السلطة ، و أماكن مثل البانتاغون.
A robots revolution is upon us.
ثورة الروبوتات قادمة نحونا.
Now, I need to be clear here.
الآن، علي أن أكون واضحا هنا.
I'm not talking about a revolution where you
أنا لا أتحدث عن ثورة حيث
have to worry about the Governor of
عليكم أن تتخوفوا من أن
California showing up at your door,
يظهر أمام منزلكم حاكم كاليفورنيا
a la the Terminator. (Laughter)
على طريقة "فيلم المدمر" .(ضحك)
When historians look at this period, they're
عندما ينظر المؤرخون لهذه الحقبة،
going to conclude that we're in a different
سيستخلصون أننا بصدد
type of revolution: a revolution in war,
نوع مختلف من الثورات : ثورة في الحرب
like the invention of the atomic bomb.
كما هو الحال بالنسبة لاختراع القنبلة الذرية.
But it may be even bigger than that,
لكن يمكن أن يكون الأمر أكبر من هذا
because our unmanned systems don't just
لأن نظمنا غير المزودة بطيار لا
affect the "how" of war-fighting,
تؤثر فقط في " كيفية" القتال الحربي
they affect the "who" of fighting
بل في" هوية" من يقاتل
at its most fundamental level.
على المستوى الأكثر أهمية.
That is, every previous revolution in war, be
هذا ما يعني، أن في الثورات الحربية السابقة، لنقل
it the machine gun, be it the atomic bomb,
الأسلحة الرشاشة، لنقل القنبلة النووية،
was about a system that either shot faster,
كان الأمر يتعلق بأنظمة تقصف بشكل أسرع
went further, had a bigger boom.
ذات مدى أبعد، أو تحدث انفجارات أضخم.
That's certainly the case with robotics, but
وهذا بالتأكيد هو الحال مع الروبوتات ، لكنها
they also change the experience of the warrior
أيضا غيرت تجربة المحارب
and even the very identity of the warrior.
بل غيرت الهوية العميقة للمحارب.
Another way of putting this is that
طريقة أخرى لشرح هذا
mankind's 5,000-year-old monopoly
أن احتكار الإنسان لمدة 5000 سنة
on the fighting of war is breaking down
للقتال في الحروب بدأ في الانهيار
in our very lifetime. I've spent
في عصرنا هذا.لقد قضيت
the last several years going around
السنوات العديدة الماضية بالتجوال
meeting with all the players in this field,
ولقاء كل الفاعلين في هذا المجال،
from the robot scientists to the science
من علماء الروبوتات،
fiction authors who inspired them to the
إلى كتاب الخيال العلمي الذين ألهموهم
19-year-old drone pilots who are fighting
إلى الطيارين الذين حاربوا منذ 19 سنة
from Nevada, to the four-star generals
من نيفادا ، إلى الجنرالات ذوي الأربع نجمات
who command them, to even the Iraqi
الذين قادوهم ، حتى إلى المتمردين
insurgents who they are targeting and what
العراقيين الذين استهدفوهم ، و مالذي
they think about our systems, and
يعتقدونه حيال أنظمتنا،
what I found interesting is not just
وما وجدته مثيرا للاهتمام ، ليست فقط
their stories, but how their experiences
قصصهم، بل كيف كانت تجاربهم
point to these ripple effects that are going
تشير إلى هذه الآثار الدخيلة
outwards in our society, in our law
عن مجتمعاتنا ، و قوانيننا
and our ethics, etc. And so what I'd like
و قيمنا، إلخ. وما أود أن
to do with my remaining time is basically
أن أفعله في الوقت المتبقي لي بالأساس
flesh out a couple of these.
هو أن أجسد بعضا من هذه الأشياء.
So the first is that the future of war,
أولها ، أن مستقبل الحروب ،
even a robotics one, is not going to be
حتى الروبوتية منها، لن تكون
purely an American one.
أمريكية صرفة.
The U.S. is currently ahead in military
حاليا تحتل الولايات المتحدة الصدارة من الناحية
robotics right now, but we know that in
العسكرية الروبوتية، لكننا نعلم
technology there's no such thing as
أن في المجال التكنولوجي ليس هناك شيء يدعى
a permanent first move or advantage.
الخطوة الأولى أو الميزة الدائمة.
In a quick show of hands, how many
في استعراض سريع للأيدي، كم
people in this room still use
عدد الحاضرين في هذه القاعة من الذين لا يزالون يستعملون
Wang Computers? (Laughter)
حاسوب وانج؟ ( ضحك)
It's the same thing in war. The British and
كذلك الأمر في ما يتعلق بالحرب.البريطانيون
the French invented the tank.
و الفرنسيون اخترعوا الدبابة.
The Germans figured out how
والألمانيون عرفوا كيف
to use it right, and so what we have to
يستعملونها الاستعمال الأفضل، وبالتالي ما علينا
think about for the U.S. is that we are
التفكير به بالنسبة للولايات المتحدة، أننا
ahead right now, but you have
في المقدمة الآن، لكن هناك
43 other countries out there
43 دولة
working on military robotics, and they
تعمل على تطوير الجيش الروبوتي،من ضمنها
include all the interesting countries like
كل الدول المثيرة للاهتمام مثل
Russia, China, Pakistan, Iran.
روسيا ،الصين، باكستان، إيران
And this raises a bigger worry for me.
وهذا يبعث بداخلي قلقا كبيرا.
How do we move forward in this revolution
كيف يمكننا المضي قدما في هذه الثورة
given the state of our manufacturing
آخذين بعين الاعتبار وضعية صناعتنا
and the state of our science and
ووضعية تعليم العلوم
mathematics training in our schools?
و الرياضيات في مدارسنا؟
Or another way of thinking about this is,
طريقة أخرى للتفكير حيال هذا الأمر
what does it mean to go to war increasingly
مالذي يعنيه الذهاب للحرب بشكل مضطرد
with soldiers whose hardware is made
بجنود ذوي أقراص صلبة صينية الصنع
in China and software is written in India?
مع برامج معلوماتية معدة في الهند؟
But just as software has gone open-source,
ولكن بما أن البرامج المعلوماتية أصبحت مفتوحة المصدر
so has warfare.
كذلك أصبح الأمر بالنسبة للحروب.
Unlike an aircraft carrier or an atomic bomb,
بخلاف حاملات الطائرات أو القنبلة الذرية،
you don't need a massive manufacturing
لا تحتاج إلى نظام صناعي هائل
system to build robotics. A lot of it is
لصنع الروبوتات. جزء كبير
off the shelf. A lot of it's even do-it-yourself.
منها هناك على الرف.جزء كبير منها يمكنك صناعته بنفسك.
One of those things you just saw flashed
واحدة من الأشياء التي رأيتم مقتطفات منها
before you was a raven drone, the handheld
كانت طائرة بدون طيار على هيئة غراب
tossed one. For about a thousand dollars,
ذات يد قاذفة.مقابل ألف دولار
you can build one yourself, equivalent to
يمكنك صناعة واحدة بنفسك، متكافئة
what the soldiers use in Iraq.
مع تلك التي يستعملها الجنود في العراق.
That raises another wrinkle when it comes
هذا يجرنا إلى مسألة أخرى عندما يتعلق الأمر
to war and conflict. Good guys might play
بالنزاعات و الحروب. قد يحاول الناس الخيرون
around and work on these as hobby kits,
اللعب بهذه الآلات و اعتبارها هواية
but so might bad guys.
لكن هذا ما قد يفعله الأشرار أيضا.
This cross between robotics and things like
هذا التقاطع بين الروبوت و أشياء مثل
terrorism is going to be fascinating
الإرهاب سيكون آسرا
and even disturbing,
وحتى مزعجا.
and we've already seen it start.
ولقد شهدنا بدأ هذا الأمر قبل الآن.
During the war between Israel, a state,
خلال الحرب بين اسرائيل، الكيان
and Hezbollah, a non-state actor,
وحزب الله، الذي لا يعتبر دولة،
the non-state actor flew
رأينا كيف أن الفاعل الذي لا يعتبر دولة،أرسل
four different drones against Israel.
4 طائرات بدون طيار ضد إسرائيل.
There's already a jihadi website
هناك موقع جهادي
that you can go on and remotely
حيث يمكنك عن بعد
detonate an IED in Iraq while sitting
تفجير عبوة ناسفة في العراق في حين أنك جالس
at your home computer.
أمام حاسوبك المنزلي.
And so I think what we're going to see is
لذا أعتقد أن ما سنراه
two trends take place with this.
هو ظهور توجهين اثنين.
First is, you're going to reinforce the power
أولهما، هو تعزيز قوة
of individuals against governments,
الأفراد في مواجهة الحكومات,
but then the second is that
لكن التوجه الثاني
we are going to see an expansion
أننا سنشهد توسعا
in the realm of terrorism.
في مجال الإرهاب.
The future of it may be a cross between
مستقبل هذا سيكون بين أمرين
al Qaeda 2.0 and the
القاعدة 2.0
next generation of the Unabomber.
وجيل جديد من إرهابيي" أونابوبمر".
And another way of thinking about this
طريقة أخرى لرؤية هذا الموضوع
is the fact that, remember, you don't have
هي عليكم أن تتذكروا أنكم لستم
to convince a robot that they're gonna
بحاجة لإقناع الروبوت أنه سيحصل
receive 72 virgins after they die
على 72 من العذراوات إذا توفي
to convince them to blow themselves up.
لإقناعه بتفجير نفسه.
But the ripple effects of this are going to go
لكن نتيجة هذا الأمر ستنعكس على
out into our politics. One of the people that
سياساتنا. أحد الأشخاص الذين
I met with was a former Assistant Secretary of
التقيتهم كان مساعدا سابقا لوزير
Defense for Ronald Reagan, and he put it
الدفاع في عهد رونالد ريغن،وكان قد قال
this way: "I like these systems because
ما يلي : "لقد أعجبتني هذه الأنظمة لأنها
they save American lives, but I worry about
تنقذ حياة الأمريكيين، لكنني قلق
more marketization of wars,
من أن تؤدي إلى مزيد من تسويق للحروب،
more shock-and-awe talk,
مزيد من خطابات الرعب
to defray discussion of the costs.
لصرف النظر عن الحديث عن تكاليفها.
People are more likely to support the use
يكون الناس أكثر دعما لاستخدام
of force if they view it as costless."
القوة إذا رأوا أنها غير مكلفة".
Robots for me take certain trends
بالنسبة لي، تأخذ الروبوتات بعض الاتجاهات
that are already in play in our body politic,
التي بدأت تؤثر في نظامنا السياسي,
and maybe take them to
وقد تأخذهم
their logical ending point.
إلى نقطة نهاية منطقية.
We don't have a draft. We don't
ليست لدينا مسودات،
have declarations of war anymore.
ليست لدينا إعلانات لحروب قادمة بعد الآن.
We don't buy war bonds anymore.
لم نعد نشتري أي سندات.
And now we have the fact that we're
و الآن لدينا واقع آخر ، أننا
converting more and more of our American
بدأنا نستبدل المزيد و المزيد من
soldiers that we would send into harm's
جنودنا الأمريكيين الذين كنا سنرسلهم إلى طريق الهلاك،
way into machines, and so we may take
بآلات،وبذلك نكون قد أخذنا
those already lowering bars to war
تلك المنحنيات الدالة على الحروب، المنخفضة أصلا
and drop them to the ground.
و نوصلها إلى المستوى الصفر.
But the future of war is also going to be
لكن مستقبل الحرب سيكون أيضا
a YouTube war.
حربا على اليوتيوب.
That is, our new technologies don't merely
هذا يعني، أن التقنيات الحديثة لا تستطيع
remove humans from risk.
حتى حفظ الإنسان من الخطر.
They also record everything that they see.
تسجل هذه التقنيات كل ما ترى.
So they don't just delink the public:
فهي بذلك لا تفصل العموم فقط:
they reshape its relationship with war.
بل تعيد صياغة علاقتهم بالحرب.
There's already several thousand
توجد عدة آلاف
video clips of combat footage from Iraq
من مقاطع الفيديو تظهر لقطات للصراع الدائر في العراق
on YouTube right now,
على اليوتيوب الآن.
most of it gathered by drones.
معظمها مأخوذة عن طريق الطائرات بدون طيار.
Now, this could be a good thing.
الآن قد يكون هذا أمرا جيدا.
It could be building connections between
قد يؤدي هذا إلى ربط الاتصال بين
the home front and the war front
الجبهة الداخلية و جبهة القتال
as never before.
كما لم يكن عليه الحال سابقا على الإطلاق.
But remember, this is taking place
لكن تذكر، يحدث هذا
in our strange, weird world, and so
في عالمنا الغريب، وبالتالي
inevitably the ability to download these
حتما إمكانية تحميل هذه
video clips to, you know, your iPod
المقاطع على الآي بود
or your Zune gives you
أو زوون يمنحك
the ability to turn it into entertainment.
إمكانية أخذ الأمر على محمل التسلية و الترفيه.
Soldiers have a name for these clips.
يعطي الجنود اسما لهذه المقاطع.
They call it war porn.
يسمونها مقاطع فاحشة.
The typical one that I was sent was
أحد المقاطع النموذجية التي أرسلت إلي
an email that had an attachment of
كانت مرفقة في رسالة الكترونية
video of a Predator strike taking out
عبارة عن فيديو يوضح طائرة الهجمة المفترسة تهاجم
an enemy site. Missile hits,
موقعا للعدو. صواريخ تقذف
bodies burst into the air with the explosion.
وأجسام تتطاير في الهواء من وقع الانفجار.
It was set to music.
كان الفيديو مرفوقا بموسيقى
It was set to the pop song
بأغنية بوب
"I Just Want To Fly" by Sugar Ray.
"أريد أن أطير " لشوغار راي.
This ability to watch more
إن إمكانية مشاهدة المزيد
but experience less creates a wrinkle
مع قلة التجربة تحدث تصادما
in the public's relationship with war.
في علاقة العموم مع الحرب.
I think about this with a sports parallel.
أفكر في الأمر بالموازاة مع الرياضة.
It's like the difference between
فالأمر أشبه بالفرق بين
watching an NBA game, a professional
مشاهدة مباراة كرة سلة احترافية
basketball game on TV, where the athletes
على التلفاز، حيث يبدو اللاعبون
are tiny figures on the screen, and
عبارة عن أشكال صغيرة على الشاشة ، وبين
being at that basketball game in person
حضور تلك المباراة شخصيا
and realizing what someone seven feet
ومعاينة كيف يبدو من
really does look like.
يبلغ طوله 7 أقدام فعلا.
But we have to remember,
لكن علينا أن نتذكر
these are just the clips.
هذه مجرد مقاطع.
These are just the ESPN SportsCenter
هذه فقط نسخة وكالة شبكة الأخبار الرياضية
version of the game. They lose the context.
نسخة أضاعت السياق.
They lose the strategy.
أضاعت الاستراتيجية.
They lose the humanity. War just
أضاعت الإنسانية.أصبحت الحرب
becomes slam dunks and smart bombs.
عبارة عن فرق "سلام دانك" و عن قنابل ذكية.
Now the irony of all this is that
ما يثير السخرية الآن في هذا كله
while the future of war may involve
بينما نرى أن مستقبل الحروب قد يلتزم
more and more machines,
المزيد و المزيد من الآلات،
it's our human psychology that's driving
فإن سيكولوجيا الإنسان هي التي تقود
all of this, it's our human failings
هذا الأمر كله، أخطاؤنا
that are leading to these wars.
هي التي تؤدي بنا إلى هذه الحروب.
So one example of this that has
أحد الأمثلة عن هذا والتي كان له
big resonance in the policy realm is
صدى في الحقل السياسي
how this plays out on our very real
كيف يلعب هذا دورا في حربنا الحقيقية
war of ideas that we're fighting
على الأفكار التي نحارب
against radical groups.
من أجلها ضد المجموعات الراديكالية.
What is the message that we think we are
ماهي الرسالة التي نعتقد أننا
sending with these machines versus what
نرسلهامن خلال هذه الآلات ، بالمقارنة مع
is being received in terms of the message.
مالذي يتم تلقيه من حيث مفردات هذه الرسالة.
So one of the people that I met was
أحد الأشخاص الذين التقيتهم كان
a senior Bush Administration official,
مسؤولا كبيرا في إدارة بوش،
who had this to say about
كان أن قال ما يلي عن
our unmanning of war:
طريقة حروبنا بدون تدخل الإنسان.
"It plays to our strength. The thing that
"إنها تعمل لصالح قوتنا.
scares people is our technology."
مايخيف الناس هي تقنياتنا".
But when you go out and meet with people,
لكنك عندما تذهب و تلتقي مع ناس آخرين
for example in Lebanon, it's a very
في لبنان مثلا ، تجد
different story. One of the people
قصة مختلفة تماما. أحد الأشخاص
I met with there was a news editor, and
الذين التقيتهم هناك ، كان رئيس تحرير أخبار
we're talking as a drone is flying above him,
وكنا نتحدث كما لو أن طائرة بدون طيار تحلق فوقه
and this is what he had to say.
وكان أن قال ما يلي :
"This is just another sign of the coldhearted
"هذا دليل آخر على القلوب الباردة
cruel Israelis and Americans,
و الوحشية التي يمتلكها الإسرائيليون والأمريكيون
who are cowards because
الجبناء لأنهم
they send out machines to fight us.
يرسلون آلات ليحاربونا.
They don't want to fight us like real men,
لا يريدون محاربتنا كرجال حقيقيين،
but they're afraid to fight,
لكنهم يخافون القتال
so we just have to kill a few of their soldiers
لذا يكون علينا فقط قتل بضعة من جنودهم
to defeat them."
لنهزمهم"
The future of war also is featuring
مستقبل الحرب يتطلب أيضا إظهار
a new type of warrior,
نوعا جديدا من المحاربين،
and it's actually redefining the experience
وفي الواقع فإنه يعيد تعريف تجربة
of going to war.
الذهاب إلى الحرب.
You can call this a cubicle warrior.
يمكننا تسمية هذا بمهجع المحارب.
This is what one Predator drone pilot
هذا ما وصف به قائد طائرة "بريدايتور" بدون طيار
described of his experience fighting
تجربته القتالية
in the Iraq War while never leaving Nevada.
في حرب العراق دون أن يضطر إلى مغادرة نيفادا إطلاقا.
"You're going to war for 12 hours,
"تذهب إلى الحرب لمدة 12 ساعة،
shooting weapons at targets,
تقذف بالأسلحة على الأهداف،
directing kills on enemy combatants,
توجه القتل على مقاتلي العدو،
and then you get in the car
بعدها تركب سيارتك
and you drive home and within 20 minutes,
عائدا إلى المنزل و خلال 20 دقيقة ،
you're sitting at the dinner table
تكون على طاولة العشاء ،
talking to your kids about their homework."
تتحدث مع أبنائك عن واجبهم المدرسي ."
Now, the psychological balancing
الآن ، التوازن النفسي
of those experiences is incredibly tough,
لهذه التجارب يكون صعبا للغاية،
and in fact those drone pilots have
في الواقع، يصاب قائدوا الطيارات بدون طيار
higher rates of PTSD than many
بمعدلات أعلى من اضطرابات ما بعد الصدمة مما تكون عليه
of the units physically in Iraq.
الوحدات الموجودة فعليا في العراق.
But some have worries that this
لكن البعض قلق من أن
disconnection will lead to something else,
يؤدي هذا الانقطاع إلى شيء آخر،
that it might make the contemplation of war
هو أنه قد يجعل تأمل الحرب
crimes a lot easier when you have
الجرائم أكثر سهولة عندما تكون لديك
this distance. "It's like a video game,"
هذه المسافة."إنها أشبه بلعبة فيديو"
is what one young pilot described to me
هكذا وصف لي طيار شاب
of taking out enemy troops from afar.
كيفية النيل من قوات العدو عن بعد.
As anyone who's played Grand Theft Auto
و كما يعرف أي شخص لعب لعبة " سرقة السيارات الكبرى"
knows, we do things in the video world
نقوم من خلال عالم الفيديو بفعل أشياء
that we wouldn't do face to face.
لم نكن لنقوم بها في الواقع.
So much of what you're hearing from me
كثير مما تسمعون مني الآن
is that there's another side
يعني أن هناك جانبا آخرا
to technologic revolutions,
للثورات التكنولوجية
and that it's shaping our present
يقوم بجعل حاضرنا أكثر وضوحا
and maybe will shape our future of war.
و ربما يجعل مستقبل الحرب أيضا كذلك.
Moore's Law is operative,
قانون مور فعال،
but so's Murphy's Law.
وكذلك قانون مورفي.
The fog of war isn't being lifted.
ضباب الحرب لم يزل بعد.
The enemy has a vote.
والعدو يملك قرارا.
We're gaining incredible new capabilities,
إننا نحصل على إمكانيات جديدة رائعة
but we're also seeing and experiencing
لكننا أيضا نرى و نعاين
new human dilemmas. Now,
مفارقات إنسانية جديدة. الآن
sometimes these are just "oops" moments,
في بعض الأحيان تكون هذه لحظات دهشة سريعة " أووبس"،
which is what the head of a robotics
هكذا وصفها رئيس
company described it, you just have
رئيس شركة روبوتات، كل مالديك
"oops" moments. Well, what are
بضع من لحظات "أووبس" . حسنا ما هي
"oops" moments with robots in war?
لحظات الدهشة هذه مع الروبوتات في الحرب؟
Well, sometimes they're funny. Sometimes,
حسنا، أحيانا تكون مضحكة. أحيانا،
they're like that scene from the
تكون شبيهة بذلك المشهد من
Eddie Murphy movie "Best Defense,"
فيلم إدي مورفي " بيست ديفانس"
playing out in reality, where they tested out
في دور واقعي، حينما جربوا
a machine gun-armed robot, and during
روبوتا مجهزا بمسدس، وخلال
the demonstration it started spinning
التجربة بدأ يصنع
in a circle and pointed its machine gun
دائرة، ووجه مسدسه على
at the reviewing stand of VIPs.
موقع استعراض كبار الشخصيات .
Fortunately the weapon wasn't loaded
لحسن الحظ لم يكن السلاح محشوا
and no one was hurt, but other times
ولم يصب أحد،لكن في مناسبات أخرى
"oops" moments are tragic,
تكون لحظات الدهشة مأساوية،
such as last year in South Africa, where
كماحدث السنة الماضية في جنوب إفريقيا حين
an anti-aircraft cannon had a
تعرض مدفع مضاد للطائرات
"software glitch," and actually did turn on
لخلل في برنامجه المعلوماتي، فكان أن اشتغل بمفرده
and fired, and nine soldiers were killed.
وأطلق النار ، فقتل 9 من الجنود.
We have new wrinkles in the laws of war
لدينا تصادمات جديدة في قوانين الحرب
and accountability. What do we do
و مسؤولياتها.ما فائدة
with things like unmanned slaughter?
أشياء مثل مذابح بدون تدخل الإنسان؟
What is unmanned slaughter?
ماهي المذابح بدون تدخل الإنسان؟
We've already had three instances of
رأينا مسبقا ثلاث حالات
Predator drone strikes where we thought
لطائرات "بيدياتور" من دون طيار حين اعتقدنا
we got bin Laden, and it turned out
أننا قبضنا على بن لادن، وتبين لنا
not to be the case.
أننا لم نتمكن من ذلك.
And this is where we're at right now.
هذه هي النقطة التي نتواجد بها الآن.
This is not even talking about armed,
لن نتحدث عن الأنظمة
autonomous systems
المسلحة المستقلة
with full authority to use force.
ذات تحكم كامل في استعمال القوة.
And do not believe that that isn't coming.
لا تعتقدوا أن هذا الأمر غير وارد.
During my research I came across
خلال أبحاثي اطلعت صدفة
four different Pentagon projects
على أربع مشاريع مختلفة للبانتاغون
on different aspects of that.
عن أربع جوانب مختلفة لهذا الأمر.
And so you have this question:
لذا إليكم هذا السؤال :
what does this lead to issues like
إلى ماذا سيقودنا هذا في قضايا مثل
war crimes? Robots are emotionless, so
جرائم الحرب؟ الروبوتات منعدمة الإحساس، لذا
they don't get upset if their buddy is killed.
فهي لن تستاء إذا قتل أحد أصدقائها.
They don't commit crimes of rage
هي لا ترتكب جرائما بدافع الغضب
and revenge.
أو الانتقام.
But robots are emotionless.
الروبوتات منعدمة الإحساس.
They see an 80-year-old grandmother
فهي ترى جدة في الثمانين من عمرها
in a wheelchair the same way they see
على كرسي متحرك كما ترى
a T-80 tank: they're both
مدرعة: T-80 كلاهما
just a series of zeroes and ones.
مجرد سلسلة من الأصفار و الآحاد.
And so we have this question to figure out:
لذا فلدينا هذا السؤال لنعرف :
How do we catch up our 20th century
كيف لنا أن نلحق قوانين الحرب للقرن العشرين
laws of war, that are so old right now
التي هي قديمة الآن،
that they could qualify for Medicare,
بطريقة تستطيع إعداد الرعاية الطبية
to these 21st century technologies?
لتواكب تكنولوجيا القرن العشرين.
And so, in conclusion, I've talked about
لذا، و في الختام ، فقد تحدثت
what seems the future of war,
عن ما يبدو مستقبل الحرب،
but notice that I've only used
لكن لاحظوا أنني استعملت فقط
real world examples and you've only seen
أمثلة من العالم الحقيقي، ولقد رأيتم فقط
real world pictures and videos.
صورا و مقاطع فيديو من العالم الحقيقي.
And so this sets a great challenge for
وهذا يضعنا جميعا أمام تحديات كبرى
all of us that we have to worry about well
علينا أن نقلق بشأنها
before you have to worry about your
قبل أن تقلقوا بشأن
Roomba sucking the life away from you.
المكنسة الكهربائية التي ترشف حياتكم بعيدا عنكم.
Are we going to let the fact that what's
هل سنترك ما
unveiling itself right now in war
تكشف لنا حتى الآن عن الحرب
sounds like science fiction and therefore
يبدو كالخيال العلمي وبالتالي
keeps us in denial?
يتركنا في حالة من الإنكار؟
Are we going to face the reality
هل سنواجه حقيقة
of 21st century war?
الحرب في القرن الواحد و العشرين؟
Is our generation going to make the same
هل سيرتكب جيلنا نفس
mistake that a past generation did
الأخطاء التي ارتكبها الجيل السابق
with atomic weaponry, and not deal with
بالأسلحة النووية، دون أن تتعامل مع
the issues that surround it until
المشاكل المحيطة بها إلى أن
Pandora's box is already opened up?
إلى أن انفتحت علبة "باندورا"؟
Now, I could be wrong on this, and
الآن ، يمكن أن أكون مخطئا في هذا الأمر،وقد
one Pentagon robot scientist told me
أخبرني أحد علماء الروبوت في البانتاغون
that I was. He said, "There's no real
أنني كنت مخطئا فعلا. قال " لا توجد أي
social, ethical, moral issues when it comes
مشاكل اجتماعية، أو أخلاقية أو معنوية عندما يتعلق الأمر
to robots.
بالروبوتات.
That is," he added, "unless the machine
و أضاف " إلا في حال ،
kills the wrong people repeatedly.
قتلت هذه الآلات الأهداف الخاطئة بشكل متكرر.
Then it's just a product recall issue."
حينها يكون المشكل فقط مشكل استرجاع منتج."
And so the ending point for this is
و بالتالي فنقطة النهاية بالنسبة لهذا
that actually, we can turn to Hollywood.
أننا في الواقع علينا العودة إلى هوليود.
all the top characters and created
أشهر الشخصيات وأعدت
a list of the top 100 heroes and
لائحة لأفضل 100 من أبطال
top 100 villains of all of Hollywood history,
و 100 من الأشرار الذين ظهروا في تاريخ هوليود كله
the characters that represented the best
الشخصيات التي مثلت المثال الأفضل
and worst of humanity.
و الأسوأ عن الإنسانية.
Only one character made it onto both lists:
شخصية واحدة فقط ظهرت في اللائحتين معا:
The Terminator, a robot killing machine.
"ذ تيرميناتور" الروبوت القاتل.
And so that points to the fact that
وهذا يشير إلى
our machines can be used
أن آلاتنا يمكن أن تستخدم
for both good and evil, but for me
لأغراض جيدة و سيئة معا،ولكن بالنسبة لي
it points to the fact that there's a duality
هذا يشيرإلى ازدواجية
of humans as well.
الإنسان أيضا.
This week is a celebration
هذا أسبوع الاحتفاء
of our creativity. Our creativity
بإبداعنا. إبداعنا
has taken our species to the stars.
الذي أخذ الجنس البشري إلى النجوم.
Our creativity has created works of arts
إبداعنا خلق أعمالا فنية
and literature to express our love.
و أدبا للتعبير عن حبنا.
And now, we're using our creativity
و الآن نحن نستخدم إبداعنا
in a certain direction, to build fantastic
في اتجاه معين، لبناء
machines with incredible capabilities,
آلات رائعة بقدرات هائلة،
maybe even one day
وربما في يوم ما حتى
an entirely new species.
لإيجاد أجناس بأكملها.
But one of the main reasons that we're
لكن أحد الأسباب الرئيسية
doing that is because of our drive
التي تجعلنا نقوم بهذا هي دافعنا
to destroy each other, and so the question
لتدمير بعضنا البعض، وهنا السؤال
we all should ask:
الذي علينا طرحه جميعا:
is it our machines, or is it us
أهي آلاتنا أم نحن
that's wired for war?
من يتحمس للحرب؟
Thank you. (Applause)
شكرا لكم (تصفيق)